Aleksandra Selezneva

DATA SCIENTIST / DATA ANALYST

Profile

Data scientist with economics background and 2 years of experience in fintech inspired by challenges, sports, traveling and becoming the best version of myself. I believe that the data tells its' stories itself, we only need to listen carefully to it. Place of residence/work permit: Netherlands. Open to Relocation.

Employment History

Junior Data Scientist, Lime Credit Group, Russia

SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

- Advanced a credit scoring model by testing a hypothesis, finding a new dependence and dividing the model in two, as a result, the profitability was increased by 1.5% without any losses;
- Designed an antifraud model training on strong imbalance data with clustering and autoencoders;
- Developed a clustering model training on economic and social factors which is implemented in collection scoring;
- Created visualizations and statistical analysis to prove product hypotheses and identify new dependencies.

Libs: sklearn, catboost, lightgbm, xgboost, shap, boruta, umap, psycopg2

Intern Data Scientist, Center of Financial Technologies, Russia

SEPTEMBER 2020 - JUNE 2021

- Developed an MVP for a NPL model predicting the sentiment of text and audio reviews on banks and mobile operators;
- Responsible for predicting nationality using CNN and RNN in developing a model predicting nationality and gender by full name.

Libs: sklearn, keras, torch, gensim, kaldi-vosk, pymorphy2, flask

Education

Data Science, Yandex School of Data Analysis (ex Computer Science Center) - Yandex & JetBrains joint program, Russia

SEPTEMBER 2020 - JUNE 2024

Analog to Master's degree. Expected to graduate in 2024. Relevant coursework: Algorithms and Data Structures, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, Reinforcement Learning.

BSc Economics, Novosibirsk State University, Russia

SEPTEMBER 2016 - JUNE 2020

Successfully defended Bachelor Thesis with focus on Workforce productivity in Russian regions and industries. Participated in case competitions. Volunteered as a Math teacher in NSU Summer School.

Details

Amsterdam
Netherlands
+31 6 16 17 01 34
a.selezneva@hotmail.com

Links

GitHub

LinkedIn

Skills

Python, R, SQL

PyCharm, Jupyter Notebook

Linux, Git, Docker, DVC

Jira, Confluence

Data Processing and Analytics (numpy, pandas, scipy)

Data Vizualization (seaborn, matplotlib, dash, plotly)

Credit Scoring

A/B testing

Math Statistics, Probability Theory, Econometrics (with Time Series and Panel Data)

Languages

English - Full Professional

Russian - Native